<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefan Lesser</title>
    <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefan Lesser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stefan-lesser.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure and Behavior</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/06/structure-and-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/06/structure-and-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Structure and Behavior In 2018 I wrote a vision document for a start-up I was planning to found shortly after (spoiler: I chose to not become a founder and am now an investor instead). The vision was grand: democratize programming and bring the power of computation to everyone, not just developers.
Part of the vision document described the approach of how we wanted to tackle such a large challenge and cut it up into smaller pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category Theory: Resources</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/notes/category-theory-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/notes/category-theory-resources/</guid>
      <description>Category Theory: Resources I’m currently trying to fully understand category theory as it applies to programming. I’m not scared of math, however, I’m also not a mathematician, so I’m looking for an introduction that helps me build intuitive understanding first, and then goes all the way into the formalisms.
Here are the resources I am currently reading that I found the most helpful so far:
Resources Why Category Theory Matters • rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m Stefan. A passionate programmer, application architect, and former Apple Technology Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Apple&#39;s Love Affair With Swift</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2018/06/20/on-apples-love-affair-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2018/06/20/on-apples-love-affair-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to write a thoughtful article in response to Dominik Wagner&#39;s &amp;ldquo;On my misalignment with Apple&#39;s love affair with Swift&amp;rdquo;. During my research I realized, that Chris Lattner had already done this. Sort of. 17 months before Dominik published his piece.
Thanks to Marco Arment, Casey Liss, and John Siracusa for recording a fabulous &amp;ldquo;not an interview show&amp;rdquo; with Chris &amp;ldquo;extraordinary circumstance&amp;rdquo; Lattner back in January 2017, asking the right questions, and even publishing a transcript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>