<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefan Lesser</title>
    <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefan Lesser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stefan-lesser.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing as Thinking</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2020/01/07/writing-as-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2020/01/07/writing-as-thinking/</guid>
      <description>It crossed my mind to revive this blog with a meta post about writing. But there are too many blogs out there that haven&#39;t published anything in a long time, and the last post describes in great detail how the author plans to focus more on writing and finally publish more content on a regular schedule. Not where I want to end up…
Tricking myself into writing Late last year I sent an email to a few friends letting them in on my mischievous plan to manipulate myself to write more and share the results publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Future of Programming</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/24/a-future-of-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/24/a-future-of-programming/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of my blog chain Beyond Code. Start here.
 The A Future of Programming There are so many directions to explore to democratize programming. It&#39;s useful to be opinionated, make some choices upfront, and shrink the solution space a bit. You might disagree with my choices here, and that&#39;s ok. I write them down so we can find out quickly. That doesn&#39;t mean other directions are wrong or less promising, this is just the direction I am headed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories Everywhere</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/20/categories-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/20/categories-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>Part 3 of my Universal Structure blog chain. Start here.
 Language Human language, spoken or written, is an amazingly sophisticated invention that has evolved over centuries. We can describe concepts, transmit those descriptions through space and time, and create shared understanding. It&#39;s not perfect, but it does work reasonably well to help us communicate.
It&#39;s no coincidence that we &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; to computers with programming languages. Let&#39;s forget about programming for a moment and focus just on human language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/17/the-art-of-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/17/the-art-of-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>In a recent discussion on The Future of Coding Slack my understanding of abstraction was challenged. As I currently write about categorization, this was a good reason to reflect on what abstraction means to me. The word gets thrown around lightly in technical discussions. We&#39;re susceptible to just assume that our intuitive understanding of a word is sufficient to wield it as a weapon in debate.
What is abstraction? My understanding of the process of abstraction is that it is fundamentally about removing ignoring detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratize Programming</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/13/democratize-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/13/democratize-programming/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of my blog chain Beyond Code.
At the end of 2016, after I had left Apple, and half-way into a year of traveling, I thought about what I wanted to tackle next and wrote down1 some big ideas that got me excited. As part of a larger document I wrote:
 Make Developing Software Accessible to Everyone
aka &amp;ldquo;Fix software development&amp;rdquo;
A lot has changed in software development over the last fifty years, but we still struggle with the same complexities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/10/free-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/10/free-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of my Universal Structure blog chain. Start here.
 As I was thinking about structure and data models, I wondered about how we make decisions every day, almost effortlessly, which are fundamentally data model manipulations:
 Structuring emails or notes with headings and by moving paragraphs of text around Using lists and tables and knowing which items belong together and how to order them Creating graphs and visualizations to express certain points with &amp;ldquo;pictures worth more than a thousand words&amp;rdquo; Naming documents, files, and folders in a way sensible to us Filing away documents, emails, notes, and tasks into complex folder hierarchies Building these hierarchies in the first place and adapting them over time as our needs change  You don&#39;t have to be a computer scientist or software engineer to do any of these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure and Behavior</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/06/structure-and-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2019/12/06/structure-and-behavior/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 of my blog chain Universal Structure.
 In 2018 I wrote a vision document for a start-up I was planning to found shortly after (spoiler: I chose to not become a founder and am now an investor instead). The vision was grand: democratize programming and bring the power of computation to everyone, not just developers.
Part of the vision document described the approach of how we wanted to tackle such a large challenge and cut it up into smaller pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category Theory: Resources</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/notes/category-theory-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/notes/category-theory-resources/</guid>
      <description>Category Theory: Resources I’m currently trying to fully understand category theory as it applies to programming. I’m not scared of math, however, I’m also not a mathematician, so I’m looking for an introduction that helps me build intuitive understanding first, and then goes all the way into the formalisms.
Here are the resources I am currently reading that I found the most helpful so far:
Resources Why Category Theory Matters • rs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m Stefan. A passionate programmer, application architect, and former Apple Technology Evangelist.
 Follow this blog via RSS.
Receive semi-regular email updates.
Get in touch via Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Apple&#39;s Love Affair With Swift</title>
      <link>https://stefan-lesser.com/2018/06/20/on-apples-love-affair-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stefan-lesser.com/2018/06/20/on-apples-love-affair-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to write a thoughtful article in response to Dominik Wagner&#39;s &amp;ldquo;On my misalignment with Apple&#39;s love affair with Swift&amp;rdquo;. During my research I realized, that Chris Lattner had already done this. Sort of. 17 months before Dominik published his piece.
Thanks to Marco Arment, Casey Liss, and John Siracusa for recording a fabulous &amp;ldquo;not an interview show&amp;rdquo; with Chris &amp;ldquo;extraordinary circumstance&amp;rdquo; Lattner back in January 2017, asking the right questions, and even publishing a transcript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>